Okay. Hi everyone.
好的。嗨，大家好。
Okay. Let's get started.
好的。让我们开始吧。
Um- great to see you all here.
嗯 - 很高兴在这里见到你们。
Welcome back for um- week two of CS224N.
欢迎回来第二周的CS224N。
Um- so- so this is a little preview
嗯 - 所以这是一个小预览
of what's coming up in the class for this week and next week.
本周和下周课堂上将会发生什么。
Um- you know, this week is perhaps the worst week of this class.
嗯 - 你知道，本周也许是本课最糟糕的一周。
[LAUGHTER]. Um- so in week two of the class our hope is to actually kind of
[笑声]。嗯 - 所以在课堂的第二周，我们希望实际上是这样的
go through some of the nitty gritty of neural networks and how they're trained,
仔细研究一下神经网络的一些细节以及它们是如何训练的，
and how we can learn good neural networks by backpropagation,
以及我们如何通过反向传播学习良好的神经网络，
which means in particular we're gonna be sort of talking about the training
这尤其意味着我们会谈论培训
algorithms and doing calculus to work out gradients from proving them.
算法和做微积分来计算出证明它们的渐变。
Um, so we are looking a bi- a little bit,
嗯，我们正在寻找一点点，
at- um- um, word window classification named entity recognition.
在某种程度上，单词窗口分类命名为实体识别。
So there's a teeny bit of natural language processing in there, but basically,
所以那里有很少的自然语言处理，但基本上，
sort of week two is sort of,
有点像第二周，
um- math of deep learning and
嗯 - 深度学习和数学的数学
neural network models and sort of really neural network fundamentals.
神经网络模型和真正的神经网络基础。
Um, but the hope is that that will give you kind
嗯，但希望是那会给你带来帮助
of a good understanding of how these things really work,
很好地理解这些东西是如何工作的，
and we'll give you all the information you need to do,
我们会为您提供您需要做的所有信息，
um- the coming up homework and so then,
嗯 - 即将完成的作业，所以，
in week three we kind of flips.
在第三周，我们有点翻转。
So, then week three is going to be mainly about
那么，第三周将主要是关于
natural language processing so we then gonna talk about how
自然语言处理，所以我们将谈谈如何
to put syntactic structures over sentences,
把句法结构放在句子上，
um- for building dependency parses of sentences
嗯 - 用于构建依赖句子的句子
which is then actually what's used in homework three.
这实际上是家庭作业中使用的三个。
So we're chugging along rapidly.
所以我们正在快速地走来走去。
And then we'll talk about this idea of the probability of
然后我们将讨论这种概率的概念
a sentence which leads into neural language models.
一个导致神经语言模型的句子。
Um- so on the homeworks.
嗯 - 在家庭作业。
Homework one was due approximately two minutes ago,
家庭作业大约两分钟前，
um- so I hope everyone has submitted their homework one, I mean as,
嗯 - 所以我希望每个人都提交了他们的作业，我的意思是，
um- one just sort of admonition,
嗯 - 只是一种警告，
um- in general so you know homework one we
嗯 - 总的来说你知道我们的作业
hope you found was a good warm up and not too too hard
希望你发现是一个很好的热身，而不是太难
and so really be best to get homework one in quickly
因此，最好快速完成作业
rather than to burn lots of your late days doing homework one.
而不是燃烧很多你的日常工作做功课。
Um, and now right now out on the website,
嗯，现在就在网站上，
um there's homework two.
嗯有两个作业。
Um so, we are chugging along.
嗯，我们正在匆匆忙忙。
So homework two kind of corresponds to this week's lectures.
家庭作业有两种与本周的讲座相对应。
So on the first part of that we are expecting you to
所以在我们期待你的第一部分
grind through some math problems of working out gradient derivations.
研究解决梯度推导的一些数学问题。
Um- and then the second part of that is then implementing
嗯 - 然后第二部分就是实施
your own version of word2vec making use of NumPy.
你自己的word2vec版本使用NumPy。
And so this time sort of writing a Python program.
所以这次写一个Python程序。
It's no longer an IPython notebook.
它不再是IPython笔记本了。
Um, I encourage you to get early,
嗯，我鼓励你早点，
um- look at the materials,
嗯 - 看看材料，
um- on the web.
嗯 - 在网上。
I mean, in particular corresponding to today's lecture there's,
我的意思是，特别是对应今天的讲座，
um- some quite good tutorial materials that are available
嗯 - 一些非常好的教程材料
on the website and so also encourage you to look at those.
在网站上，所以也鼓励你看看那些。
[NOISE].
[噪声]。
Um- more generally,
嗯 - 更一般地说，
just to make a couple more comments on things.
只是为了对事情做出更多评论。
I mean, I guess this is true of a lot of classes at Stanford but,
我的意思是，我想斯坦福大学的很多课程都是如此，但是，
you know when we get the course reviews for this class we always get
你知道，当我们得到这门课程的评论时，我们总能得到
the full spectrum from people who say the class is terrible and it's way too much work,
来自那些认为课程很糟糕并且工作太多的人的全部谱
um- to the people who say it's a really great class,
对那些说这是一个非常好的班级的人来说，
one of their favorite classes at Stanford,
他们在斯坦福大学最喜欢的课程之一，
obvious the instructors care, et cetera.
明显的教师关心，等等。
And I mean, partly this reflects that we get this very,
我的意思是，部分这反映了我们得到了这个，
um- wide range of people coming to take this class on the one hand,
嗯 - 一方面有很多人来上这门课，
on the right hand margin perhaps we have the physics PhDs,
在右边缘或许我们有物理学博士，
and on the left hand margin we have some fresh who think this will be fun to do anyway.
在左手边缘，我们有一些新鲜的人认为这无论如何都会很有趣。
Um, we welcome e- we welcome everybody,
嗯，我们欢迎e-我们欢迎大家，
um- but in principle this is uh, graduate level class.
嗯 - 但原则上这是呃，研究生班级。
You know, that doesn't mean we want to fail people out,
你知道，这并不意味着我们想让人们失败，
we'd like everyone to succeed but also like graduate level class.
我们希望每个人都能成功，但也喜欢研究生班级。
Um- we'd like you to- you know,
嗯 - 我们希望你 - 你知道，
take some initiative in your success.
在你的成功中采取一些主动。
Meaning, if there are things that you need to know to
意思是，如果你需要知道的事情
do the assignments and you don't know them,
做任务，你不知道，
um- then you should be taking some initiative to find some tutorials,
嗯 - 那么你应该采取一些主动寻找一些教程，
come to office hours and talk to people and get
上班时间与人交谈并获得
any help you need and learn to sort of for any holes in your knowledge.
您需要的任何帮助，并学习如何解决您的知识漏洞。
Okay. So here's the plan for today.
好的。所以这是今天的计划。
Um- so that was the course information update.
嗯 - 这是课程信息更新。
So you know, is- this is sort of,
所以你知道，是 - 这是一种，
in some sense you know machine learning neural nets intro- Just to
在某种意义上，你知道机器学习神经网络介绍 - 只是为了
try and make sure everyone else is up to speed on all of this stuff.
尽量确保其他人都能快速掌握所有这些内容。
So I'll talk a little bit about classification, um,
所以我会谈谈分类，嗯，
introduce neural networks, um,
介绍神经网络，嗯，
little detour into named Entity Recognition,
很少绕道命名的实体识别，
then sort of show a model of doing um
然后有点展示做某事的模型
Window- Word Window classification and then the end part,
窗口 -  Word窗口分类然后是结束部分，
we sort of then dive deeper into what kind of tools we
然后我们会更深入地了解我们的工具类型
need to learn neural networks and so today um we're gonna go
需要学习神经网络，所以今天我们要去
through um somewhere between review and primer of matrix calculus and then that will
通过审查和矩阵演算的引物之间的某个地方，然后那将
lead into next time's lecture where it's talking
进入下一次讲座的地方
more about backpropagation and computation graphs.
更多关于反向传播和计算图。
So, yeah. So this material was especially the part at the end.
是的。所以这种材料特别是最后的部分。
You know for some people it'll seem really
你知道有些人看起来真的如此
babyish if- it's the kind of stuff you do every week, um,
如果这是你每周都做的那种东西，嗯，
for other people it um- might seem impossibly
对于其他人来说，它似乎是不可能的
difficult but hopefully for a large percentage of you in the middle
很难，但希望你中间有很大一部分人
this will be kind of a useful review of doing this kind of
对于这样做，这将是一种有用的回顾
matrix calculus and the kind of things that we hope that you can do on homework two.
矩阵演算和我们希望你可以做两件事的东西。
Um, okay. So um, yeah.
嗯，好的。嗯，是的
So sorry if I'm boring some people.
很抱歉，如果我让一些人感到无聊。
If you sat through 229 last quarter you
如果你在上个季度坐了229你
saw um what a classifier was like and hopefully this
看到分类器是什么样的，希望如此
will seem familiar but I'm just sort of hoping to try and have
看起来很熟悉，但我只是希望尝试一下
everyone in week two sort of up to speed and on roughly the same page.
在第二周的每个人都达到速度和大致相同的页面。
So here's our classification setup.
所以这是我们的分类设置。
So we have assumed we have a- training data set where we have these um vector
所以我们假设我们有一个训练数据集，我们有这些um向量
x um of our x points and then for each one of them we have a class.
x我们的x点，然后对于每一个我们有一个类。
So the input might be words or sentences documents or something,
所以输入可能是文字或句子文件或其他东西，
there are d to mention vector, um,
还有提到矢量，嗯，
the Yi, the labels or classes that we want to
易，我们想要的标签或类
classify to and we've got a set of C classes that we're trying to predict.
归类为，我们有一组我们试图预测的C类。
And so those might be something like the topic of the document,
所以那些可能类似于文档的主题，
the sentiment positive or negative um of
情绪的积极或消极的
a document or later we'll look a bit more at named entities.
一个文档或稍后我们将看一些命名实体。
Okay. So if we have that um-
好的。所以如果我们有那个 -
for this sort of intuition is we got this vector space which we again have
对于这种直觉，我们得到了这个我们再次拥有的向量空间
a 2D picture and we have points in that vector space which
一张2D图片，我们在那个矢量空间中有点
correspond to Rx items and what we'd want to do is we'll
对应于Rx项目，我们想要做的就是我们
look at the ones in our training sample and see which ones are
看看我们的训练样本中的那些，看看哪些是
green and red for our two classes here and then we want to sort of learn
绿色和红色为我们的两个班级，然后我们想要学习
a line that could divide between the green and
可以在绿色和绿色之间划分的线
the red ones as best as possible and that learned line is our classifier.
红色的那些尽可能最好，学习的线是我们的分类器。
So on traditional machine learning or statistics we have the sort of
因此，在传统的机器学习或统计学方面，我们就是这样的
XI vectors that are data items that are purely fixed but
XI向量是纯粹固定但是的数据项
we're going to then multiply those XI by
然后我们将乘以那些XI
some estimated weight vector and
一些估计的重量矢量和
that estimated weight vector will then go into a classification decision.
然后，估计的权重向量将进入分类决策。
And the classifier that I'm showing here is
而我在这里展示的分类器是
a softmax classifier which is almost identical but not quite to
softmax分类器几乎相同但不完全相同
logistic regression classifier which you should've seen in CS 109 or a stats
你应该在CS 109或统计数据中看到的逻辑回归分类器
class or something like that which is giving a probability of different classes.
类或类似于给出不同类概率的类。
Okay. And in particular if you've got
好的。特别是如果你有的话
a softmax classifier or a logistic- logistic regression classifier,
softmax分类器或logistic-logistic回归分类器，
these are what are called linear classifiers.
这些就是所谓的线性分类器。
So the decision boundary between two classes here
所以两个类之间的决策边界在这里
is a line in some suitably high-dimensional space.
在一些适当的高维空间中是一条线。
So it's a plane or a hyperplane once you've got a bigger expecter.
一旦你有了更大的前景，它就是飞机或超平面。
Okay. So here's our softmax classifier.
好的。所以这是我们的softmax分类器。
Um, and there are sort of two parts to that.
嗯，这有两个部分。
So in the- in the weight matrix double U
所以在重量矩阵中双U.
we have a row corresponding to each class and then for
我们有一个对应于每个类的行，然后是
that row we're sort of dot-producting it with
那一行，我们有点点产品
our data point vector XI and that's giving us a kind of a score for
我们的数据点向量XI，这给了我们一种得分
how likely it is that the example belongs to that class and then we're
这个例子属于那个类的可能性是多少，然后我们就是这样
running that through a softmax function and just as we saw on week one,
通过softmax功能运行，就像我们在第一周看到的一样，
the softmax takes a bunch of numbers and turn them into a probability distribution.
softmax需要一堆数字并将它们转换为概率分布。
Does that makes sense to people?
这对人们有意义吗？
People remember that from last week? Good so far?
人们记得从上周开始？目前很好？
Okay. Um, I'm not gonna go to this in detail but I mean,
好的。嗯，我不打算详细谈谈这个，但我的意思是，
ah- essentially this is what the logistic regression does as well.
啊 - 基本上这也是逻辑回归的作用。
Um, the difference is that here in this setup we have a weight vector um
嗯，不同的是，在这个设置中我们有一个权重向量嗯
for each class whereas what
对于每个班级而言什么
the statisticians doing logistic regression is they say weight,
进行逻辑回归的统计学家说他们说体重，
that gives us one more number of weight vectors than we really need.
这给了我们比我们真正需要的更多的权重向量。
We can get away for- for C classes,
我们可以为C课程逃脱
we can get away with C minus one weight vectors.
我们可以用C减去一个权重向量。
So in particular if you're doing binary
所以特别是如果你在做二进制文件的话
logistic regression you only need one weight vector whereas
逻辑回归你只需要一个权重向量而
this softmax regression formulation you've
这个softmax回归公式你已经
actually got two weight vectors one for each class.
实际上每个班级有两个权重向量。
Um, so there's that sort of a little difference there which we
嗯，所以那里有一点我们的差别
could get into but basically the same.
可以进入，但基本相同。
It's just say it's we're either doing softmax or logistic regression, doesn't matter.
它只是说我们要么做softmax或逻辑回归，无关紧要。
Um, so when we're training what we want to
嗯，所以当我们训练我们想要的东西时
do is we want to be able to predict um the correct class.
我们希望能够预测正确的班级。
And so the way we're gonna do that is we're gonna wanna
所以我们要这样做的方式是我们想要的
train our model so it gives us highest probability as
训练我们的模型，因此它给我们最高概率
possible to the correct class and therefore they'll give us
可以到正确的班级，因此他们会给我们
low probability po- as possible um to um the wrong classes.
低概率po-尽可能错误的类。
And so our criterion for doing that is we're going to create
所以我们这样做的标准是我们要创造的
this negative log probability um of our assignments and then
这个负的对数概率是我们的任务然后
we're gonna want to minimize the negative log probability which corresponds to maximizing
我们想要最小化对应于最大化的负对数概率
the log probability which corresponds to maximizing um the probability. Um.
对数最大化概率的对数概率。嗯。
And, but, um, sort of,
而且，但是，嗯，有点像，
pretty soon now, we're gonna start doing more stuff with deep learning frameworks,
很快，我们将开始用深度学习框架做更多的事情，
in particular PyTorch and you can discover in that,
特别是PyTorch，你可以发现，
that there's actually a thing called NLL
实际上有一种叫做NLL的东西
loss which stands for negative log-likelihood loss.
损失代表负对数似然丢失。
Basically, no one uses it because the more convenient thing to use is what's called
基本上，没有人使用它，因为使用更方便的东西就是所谓的
the cross entropy loss and so you'll
交叉熵损失，所以你会
hear everywhere that we're training with cross entropy loss.
听到我们正在训练的交叉熵损失。
So, I just wanted to briefly mention that and explain what's going on there.
所以，我只想简单地提一下并解释那里发生了什么。
Um, so the concept of cross entropy comes from
嗯，因此交叉熵的概念来自
baby Information Theory which is about the amount of information theory I know.
婴儿信息理论，这是关于我所知道的信息理论的数量。
Um, so, we're assuming that there's some true probability distribution P and our model,
嗯，所以，我们假设有一些真实的概率分布P和我们的模型，
we've built some probability distribution, Q.
我们建立了一些概率分布，Q。
That's what we've built with our soft-max regression and we want to have
这就是我们用soft-max回归构建的，我们希望拥有
a measure of whether our estimated probability distribution is a good one.
衡量我们估计的概率分布是否合适的指标。
And the way we do it in cross entropy is,
我们在交叉熵中的方式是，
we go through the classes and we say,
我们通过课程，我们说，
"what's the probability of the class according to the true model?"
“根据真实模特，班级的概率是多少？”
Using that waiting, we then work out the log of, um,
使用那个等待，然后我们计算出日志，嗯，
the probability according to our estimated model and we sum those up and negate it,
根据我们的估计模型的概率，我们总结并否定它，
and that is our cross entropy measure.
这就是我们的交叉熵测量。
Okay. Um, but- so this in general gives you
好的。嗯，但是 - 这一般给你
a measure of sort of information, um, between distributions.
分布之间的一种信息，嗯。
But in our particular case,
但在我们的特殊情况下，
remember that for each example,
记得每个例子，
we've sort of assuming that this is a piece of
我们有点假设这是一块
labeled training data so we are saying for that example,
标记的训练数据，所以我们说的是这个例子，
the right answer is class seven.
正确的答案是七年级。
So therefore, our true distribution,
因此，我们的真实分布，
our p is- for this example,
我们的p是 - 这个例子，
it's class seven with probability one and it's class,
这是七级概率一级和它的级别，
um, anything else with probability zero.
嗯，其他概率为零的东西。
So if you think about then what happens with this formula,
所以，如果你考虑一下这个公式会发生什么，
you've got this summation of all the classes.
你得到了所有课程的总结。
The PFC is gonna be either one or zero and it's gonna be one
PFC将是一个或零，它将是一个
only for the true class here and so what you're left with is,
只有真正的类在这里，所以你留下的是，
this is going to equal minus the log of qc, um,
这将等于减去qc的对数，嗯，
for the true class which is sort of what we were then computing in the previous slide.
对于真正的类，这是我们在上一张幻灯片中计算的那种。
Okay. So that's- um, yeah.
好的。所以，是的，是的。
So that's basically where you'd get with cross entropy loss.
所以这基本上是你得到的交叉熵损失。
Um, but one other concept to mention.
嗯，但另外一个概念要提。
So when you have a full data-set of a whole bunch of examples,
因此，当您拥有一大堆示例的完整数据集时，
the cross entropy loss is then taking the per example average.
然后，交叉熵损失取每个例子的平均值。
So, I guess it's what information theory people sometimes call the cross entropy rate.
所以，我猜这是人们有时称之为交叉熵率的信息理论。
So additionally, factored in there.
另外，在那里考虑因素。
If you are training it on any examples is that one on in vector that's coming in there.
如果你正在训练任何一个例子，那就是那个进入那里的向量。
Okay. Um, okay.
好的。嗯，好的。
Um, so that's cross entropy loss.
嗯，这样就是交叉熵损失。
Is that okay? Yeah.
这样可以吗？是啊。
[NOISE] There's some- there's some mixture of the actual labels in the ground?
[NOISE]有一些 - 地面上有一些实际标签的混合物？
Sure. Good question.
当然。好问题。
Right. So, the simplest case is that your gold data,
对。所以，最简单的情况是你的黄金数据，
someone has hand labeled it and,
有人用手标记了它，
um, they've labeled one and the rest is zero.
嗯，他们标记了一个，剩下的就是零。
Um, they are- you can think of cases where that isn't the case.
嗯，他们是 - 你可以想到不是这种情况的情况。
I mean, one case is you could believe that human beings
我的意思是，有一种情况是你可以相信人类
sometimes don't know the right answer so if human beings said,
如果人类说，有时候不知道正确的答案，
"I'm not sure whether this should be class three or four," you could imagine that we
“我不确定这应该是三年级还是四年级，”你可以想象我们
can make training data where we put probability half on both of them,
可以制作训练数据，我们将概率降低一半，
um, and that wouldn't be a crazy thing to do,
嗯，这不会是一件疯狂的事情，
and so then you'd have a true cross entropy loss using more of a distribution.
所以你会使用更多的分布来获得真正的交叉熵损失。
Um, the case where it's much more commonly used in actual practice is,
嗯，在实际操作中更常用的情况是，
there are many circumstances in which people wanna do semi-supervised learning.
在许多情况下，人们想要进行半监督学习。
So, I guess this is a topic that
所以，我想这是一个话题
both my group and Chris Re's group have worked on quite a lot,
我的小组和Chris Re的小组都做了很多工作，
where we don't actually have fully labeled data,
我们实际上没有完全标记数据，
but we've got some means of guessing what the labels
但我们有一些猜测标签的方法
of the data are and if we try and guess labels of data,
的数据是，如果我们尝试猜测数据的标签，
well then quite often we'll say,
那么我们经常说，
"Here's this data right in.
“这是正确的数据。
It's two-thirds chances this label,
这个标签有三分之二的机会，
but it could be these other four labels," and we'd use a probability distribution,
但它可能是其他四个标签，“我们会使用概率分布，
and yeah, then it's more general cross entropy loss.
是的，那么它是更普遍的交叉熵损失。
Okay? Um, right. So, um,
好的？嗯，对。那么，嗯，
that's cross entropy loss, pretty good with.
这是交叉熵损失，相当不错。
Um, this bottom bit is a little bit different, um,
嗯，这个底部有点不同，嗯，
which is to say, "Well now we,
也就是说，“现在我们，
this is the sort of the full data-set."
这就是完整的数据集。“
The other thing to notice, um,
另外需要注意的是，嗯，
when we have a full data- we can have a full data-set of x's,
当我们有完整数据时 - 我们可以拥有x的完整数据集，
um, and then we have a full set of weights.
嗯，然后我们有一整套重量。
Um, where here we're working a row,
嗯，我们在这里工作，
a row vector for the weights for one class,
一个类的权重的行向量，
but we're gonna work it out for all classes.
但是我们要为所有课程解决这个问题。
So, we can sort of simplify what we're writing
因此，我们可以简化我们正在编写的内容
here and we can start using matrix notation
在这里，我们可以开始使用矩阵表示法
and just work directly in terms of the matrix w. Okay.
并直接就矩阵w工作。好的。
So for traditional ML optimization,
所以对于传统的ML优化，
our parameters are these sets of weights,
我们的参数是这些权重集，
um, for the different classes.
嗯，对于不同的班级。
So for each of the classes,
所以对于每个班级，
we have a d-dimensional, um,
我们有一个d维，嗯，
row vector of weights because we're gonna
行矢量的重量，因为我们要去
sort of dot-product wi- with rd, dimensional, input vector.
与rd，维度，输入向量的点积。
So we have c times d items and our W matrix and those are the parameters of our model.
所以我们有c次d项和我们的W矩阵，这些是我们模型的参数。
So if we want to learn that model using the ideas of gradient descent,
因此，如果我们想要使用梯度下降的思想来学习该模型，
stochastic gradient descent, we're gonna do
随机梯度下降，我们要做
sort of what we started to talk about last time.
我们上次开始谈论的那种。
We have these set of parameters.
我们有这些参数。
We work out, um,
我们锻炼，嗯，
the gradient, the partial derivatives of all of these, um,
梯度，所有这些的偏导数，嗯，
of the loss with respect to all of these parameters and we
关于所有这些参数和我们的损失
use that to get a gradient update on our loss function,
用它来获取我们的损失函数的渐变更新，
and we move around the w's,
我们绕着w走动，
and moving around the w's corresponds to sort of
并且在w周围移动对应于某种类型
moving this line that separates between the classes and we fiddle
移动这条分隔类的行，我们就是小提琴
that around so as to minimize our loss which corresponds to choosing a line that
周围的，以尽量减少我们的损失，这对应于选择一条线
best separates between the items of the classes in some sense.
在某种意义上，最好区分类的项目。
Okay. So, that's a basic classifier.
好的。所以，这是一个基本的分类器。
So the first question is, well,
所以第一个问题是，好吧，
how are things gonna be different with a neural network classifier?
神经网络分类器的情况会有什么不同？
Um, so the central observation is that sort of
嗯，所以中央观察就是那种
most of the classic classifiers that people used a lot of the time,
大多数人经常使用的经典分类器，
so that includes things like Naive Bayes models, um,
所以包括朴素贝叶斯模型之类的东西，嗯，
basic support vector machines,
基本支持向量机，
Softmax or logistic regressions.
Softmax或逻辑回归。
They're sort of fairly simple classifiers.
它们是一种相当简单的分类器。
In particular those are all linear classifiers which are going to classified by drawing
特别是那些都是线性分类器，它们将通过绘图进行分类
a line or in the higher dimensional space by
一条线或在更高维空间中
drawing some kind of plane that separates examples.
绘制某种分隔例子的平面。
Having a simple classifier like that can be useful in certain circumstances.
拥有这样的简单分类器在某些情况下可能很有用。
I mean, that gives you what a machine learning as a high bias classifiers,
我的意思是，这给你机器学习的高偏差分类器，
there's lots of, talk of in CS229,
在CS229中有很多，谈论，
but if you have a data-set, um,
但如果你有一个数据集，嗯，
that's like this, you can't do a very good job at classifying
就像这样，你在分类方面做得不好
all the points correctly if you have
如果你有正确的所有点
a high bias classifier because you're gonna only draw a line.
一个高偏差分类器，因为你只会画一条线。
So you'd like to have a more powerful classifier.
所以你想拥有一个更强大的分类器。
Essentially, what's been powering a lot of the use of
从本质上讲，正在为许多人的使用提供动力
deep learning is that in a lot of cases when you have natural signals,
深度学习是指在很多情况下，当你有自然信号时，
so those are things like, um, speech,
所以这些都是，嗯，演讲，
language, images, and things like that,
语言，图像和类似的东西，
you have a ton of data so you could learn a quite sophisticated classifier.
你有大量的数据，所以你可以学习一个非常复杂的分类器。
Um, but representing the classes in terms of the input data is sort of very complex.
嗯，但是根据输入数据表示类是非常复杂的。
You could never do it by just drawing a line between the two classes.
你永远不能通过在两个类之间画一条线来做到这一点。
So, you'd like to use some more complicated kind of classifier.
所以，你想使用一些更复杂的分类器。
So neural networks, the multi-layer
所以神经网络，多层次
neural networks that we're gonna be starting to get into now,
我们现在要开始进入的神经网络，
precisely what they do is provide you a way to learn very complex,
正是他们所做的是为你提供一种学习非常复杂的方法，
you know, almost limitlessly complex classifiers.
你知道，几乎是无限复杂的分类器。
So that if you look at the decisions that they're making in terms of the original space,
因此，如果你看看他们在原始空间方面做出的决定，
they can be learning cases like this.
他们可以像这样学习案例。
Um, I put this- I put the,
嗯，我把它 - 我把它，
um, pointer on a couple of the slides here.
嗯，指针在这里的几张幻灯片上。
Um, this- this is a visualization that was done by Andrei Karpathy.
嗯，这是一个由Andrei Karpathy完成的可视化。
He was a PhD student here until a couple of years ago.
直到几年前，他还是这里的博士生。
So this is a little JavaScript, um,
所以这是一个小JavaScript，嗯，
app that you can find off his website and it's
你可以在他的网站上找到它的应用程序
actually a lot of fun to play with to see what kind of,
实际上很有趣，看看是什么样的，
um, decision boundaries you can get a neural net to come up with.
嗯，决策边界你可以得到一个神经网络。
Okay. Um, so for getting- for getting more advanced classification out of,
好的。嗯，所以为了获得更高级的分类，
um, a neural net used for natural language,
嗯，一种用于自然语言的神经网络，
there are sort of two things going- that you can do,
你可以做两件事 -
that I want to talk about which are in
我想谈谈哪些内容
some sense the same thing when it comes down to it.
归结为它时，有些意义相同。
But I'll sort of mention separately at the beginning that one of them is that we
但我会在开头分别提到其中一个就是我们
have these word vectors and then
有这些单词向量然后
the second one is that we're gonna build deeper multi-layer networks.
第二个是我们要构建更深层次的多层网络。
Okay. So, at first crucial difference said,
好的。所以，起初关键的差异说，
um, we already started to see, um,
嗯，我们已经开始看到了，嗯，
with what we were doing last week is rather than
我们上周所做的不是
sort of having a word being this is the word house,
有一句话，这就是房子这个词，
we instead say house is a vector of real numbers and what we can do is
我们改为说房子是实数的矢量，我们能做的是
change the vector that corresponds to house in
更改对应于house的向量
such a way as we can build better classifiers,
这样我们可以建立更好的分类器，
which means that we are gonna be sort of moving houses representation around
这意味着我们将成为移动房屋的代表
the space to capture things that we're interested in like word similarity,
捕捉我们感兴趣的东西的空间，如单词相似度，
analogies, and things like that.
类比，等等。
So this is actually, you know,
所以这实际上是，你知道，
kind of a weird idea compared to conventional steps or ML.
与常规步骤或ML相比，这是一种奇怪的想法。
So rather than saying we just have the parameters w,
所以，而不是说我们只有参数w，
we also say that all of these word representations are also parameters of our model.
我们还说所有这些单词表示也是我们模型的参数。
So, we're actually going to change
所以，我们实际上会改变
the representations of words to allow our classifiers to do better.
允许我们的分类器做得更好的单词表示。
So, we're simultaneously changing the weights
所以，我们同时改变了权重
and we're changing the representation of words,
我们正在改变单词的表示，
and we're optimizing both of them at once to try and make our model as,
我们正在同时优化它们，试图使我们的模型成为，
um, good as possible.
嗯，尽可能好。
So, this is the sense in which people often talk about
所以，这是人们经常谈论的感觉
the deep learning models that we're doing representation learning.
我们正在做代表性学习的深度学习模型。
I sort of said there are two ways,
我有点说有两种方法，
I was going to mention two things.
我要提两件事。
One is this sort of, um,
一个就是这种，嗯，
word vector representation learning and then the second one
单词矢量表示学习然后第二个
is that we're going to start looking at deeper multi layer neural networks.
我们将开始研究更深层次的多层神经网络。
Um, sort of hidden over here on the slide
嗯，有点隐藏在幻灯片上
is the observation that really you can think of word,
是观察，你真的可以想到的是，
word vector embedding as just putting your,
单词矢量嵌入只是把你的，
having a model with one more neural network layer.
拥有一个具有一个神经网络层的模型。
So, if you imagine that each word was a one hot vector,
所以，如果你想象每个单词都是一个热矢量，
um, with, for the different word types in your model.
嗯，对于模型中的不同单词类型。
So, you had a, uh, you know,
所以，你有一个，呃，你知道，
150,000 dimensional vector with the one-hot encoding of different words.
150,000维向量与不同单词的单热编码。
Um, then you could say you have a ma-, um,
嗯，那你可以说你有一个ma，嗯，
matrix L which is sort of your lexicon matrix and you will pass your one-hot vector for
矩阵L，它是你的词典矩阵，你将通过你的单热矢量
a word through a layer of neural net which
一个词通过一层神经网络
multiplies the one-hot vector or L1, the one-hot vector.
乘以单热矢量或L1，单热矢量。
And since this was a one-hot vector,
因为这是一个单热的矢量，
what that will have the effect of doing is taking out a column of L. So,
这样做会产生什么效果就是取出一列L.所以，
really, we've got an extra layer of matrix, um,
真的，我们有一层额外的矩阵，嗯，
in our neural net and we're learning
在我们的神经网络中，我们正在学习
the parameters of that matrix in the same way as we're learning,
该矩阵的参数与我们学习的方式相同，
um, a deep neural network for other purposes.
嗯，用于其他目的的深层神经网络。
So, mathematically that completely makes sense and
因此，数学上完全有意义
that's sort of a sensible way to think about,
这是一种明智的思考方式，
um, what you're doing, um,
嗯，你在做什么，嗯，
with word embeddings in neural networks.
用嵌入式神经网络。
Um, implementation wise, this makes
嗯，实施明智，这使得
no sense at all and no one does this because it just doesn't
没有任何意义，没有人这样做，因为它没有
make sense to do a matrix multiply when the result of the matrix multiply will be, okay.
有意义的是，当矩阵乘法的结果将是一个矩阵乘法，好吧。
This is word ID 17, um, sort of,
这是单词ID 17，嗯，有点像，
then constructing a one-hot vector of length a 150,000 with a
然后用a构造一个长度为150,000的单热矢量
one in position 17 and then doing a matrix multiplied, makes no sense.
一个位置17，然后做一个矩阵倍增，没有任何意义。
You just take up, um,
你接受了，嗯，
column or, or, the row,
列，或者，行，
as we've discussed, 17 of your matrix and that's what everyone actually does.
正如我们已经讨论过的那样，你的矩阵中有17个，这就是每个人实际做的事情。
Okay. Here's my one obligatory picture of neurons, um, for the class.
好的。这是我对班级神经元的一张强制性图片。
So, don't miss it, I'm not going to show it again, all class.
所以，不要错过它，我不打算再次展示它，全班同学。
Okay. So, the origins [LAUGHTER] of Neural Networks, um,
好的。那么，神经网络的起源[笑声]，嗯，
was in some sense to try and construct
在某种意义上，尝试和构建
an artificial neuron that seemed to in
似乎是一个人造神经元
some sense kind of capture the kind of computations,
某种意义上捕获那种计算，
um, that go on in human brains.
嗯，继续人类的大脑。
It's a very loose analogy for what was produced but, you know,
对于生产的产品来说，这是一个非常宽松的比喻，但是，你知道，
our model here is these are our,
我们这里的模型是我们的，
this is our a TB part of our human brains.
这是我们人类大脑中的结核病部分。
So, here are neurons,
所以，这是神经元，
this is a neuron cell here and so,
这是一个神经细胞，所以，
what does a neuron consist of.
神经元是由什么组成的。
Um, so, up the back,
嗯，所以，在后面，
it's got these dendrites, lots of dendrites.
它有这些枝晶，很多枝晶。
Then it's got a cell body and if there's stuff coming in on the dendrites, um,
然后它有一个细胞体，如果树枝上有东西进来，嗯，
the cell body will become active and then it all starts
细胞体将变为活跃状态然后全部开始
spiking down this long thing which is called the Axon.
贬低这个被称为Axon的长事。
So, then these axons lead to
那么，这些轴突就会导致
the dendrites of a different cell or lots of different cells, right.
对不同细胞的树突或许多不同的细胞，对。
This one, um, I'm not sure it's shown but
这个，嗯，我不确定它的显示但是
some of these are kind of going to different cells.
其中一些是去不同的细胞。
Um, and so, you then have these sort of, um,
嗯，等你有这些，嗯，
terminal buttons on the Axon which are kind of close
Axon上的终端按钮有点紧密
to the dendrites but have a little gap in them and some min-,
对树枝状结构但它们有一点间隙和一些最小的，
miracles of biochemistry happen there.
那里发生了生物化学的奇迹。
So, that's the synapse, of course,
那么，这就是突触，当然，
which you'll then have sort of activation flowing which goes into the next neuron.
然后你会有一些激活流动进入下一个神经元。
So, that was the starting off, um,
所以，那是开始，嗯，
model that people wanted to try and simulate in computation.
人们想要在计算中尝试和模拟的模型。
So, people came up with this model of an artificial neuron.
因此，人们提出了这种人工神经元的模型。
So, that we have things coming in from other neurons at some level of activations.
所以，我们在某些激活水平上从其他神经元进入的东西。
So, that's a number X0, X1, X2.
所以，这是一个数字X0，X1，X2。
Um, then synapses vary depending on how excitable
嗯，然后突触取决于兴奋程度
they are as to how easily they'll let signal cross across the synapse.
他们是多么容易让信号穿过突触。
So, that's being modeled by multiplying them by a weight W0, W1, W2.
因此，通过将它们乘以权重W0，W1，W2来建模。
Then the cell body, sort of correctly,
那么细胞体，正确的，
is sort of summing this amount of excitation it's
有点总结这个激励量
getting from the different dendrites, um,
来自不同的树突，嗯，
and then it can have its own biases to how likely it is to fire,
然后它可能有自己的偏见，以解雇它的可能性，
that's the B. Um, so,
那是B.嗯，所以，
we get that and then it has some overall kind of threshold or propensity for firing.
我们得到了它然后它有一些整体的门槛或射击倾向。
So, we sort of stick it through an activation function,
所以，我们通过激活功能来坚持下去，
um, which will sort of,
嗯，这将是，
will determine a firing rate and that will be,
将确定射击率，将是，
um, the signal that's going out on the output axon.
嗯，输出轴上的信号。
So, that was sort of the starting point of that but,
所以，那是一个起点，但是，
you know, really, um,
你知道的，真的，嗯，
for what we've ended up computing.
因为我们最终计算了什么。
We just have a little bit of baby math here which actually, um,
我们这里有一点婴儿数学，实际上，嗯，
looks very familiar to the kind of baby math you see
你看到的那种宝贝数学看起来非常熟悉
in linear algebra and statistics and so it's really no different.
在线性代数和统计学中，它确实没有什么不同。
So, in particular, um,
所以，特别是，嗯，
a neuron can very easily be a Binary Logistic Regression Unit.
神经元很容易成为二元Logistic回归单元。
Um, so that, this is sort of,
嗯，所以，这是一种，
for logistic regression you're taking for your input X,
对于逻辑回归，你需要输入X，
you multiply it by a weight vector.
你把它乘以一个权重向量。
You're adding, um, your, um,
你在补充，嗯，你的，嗯，
bias term and then you're putting it through,
偏见期，然后你把它通过，
um, a non linearity,
嗯，非线性，
like the logistic function.
喜欢后勤功能。
Um, and then, so you're calculating a logistic regression,
嗯，然后，所以你正在计算逻辑回归，
um, inside this sort of neuron model.
嗯，在这种神经元模型中。
Um, and so this is the,
嗯，这就是，
this is the difference between the soft maximum logistic regression,
这是软最大逻辑回归之间的差异，
that I was saying that there is the soft-max for two classes has two sets of parameters.
我说有两个类的soft-max有两组参数。
This sort of just has one set of parameters Z and your modeling
这种只有一组参数Z和你的建模
the two classes by giving the probability of one class from 0 to one,
两个类通过给出一个类的概率从0到1，
depending on whether the input to
取决于是否输入
logistic regression is highly negative or highly positive.
逻辑回归是高度消极或高度积极的。
Okay. So, really, we can just say these artificial neurons are sort of like
好的。所以，真的，我们可以说这些人工神经元有点像
binary logistic regression units or we can make variants of
二元逻辑回归单位或我们可以做出变体
binary logistic regression units by using some different F function.
二元逻辑回归单元通过使用一些不同的F函数。
And we'll come back to that again and pretty soon.
我们将很快再次回到那里。
Okay. Um, well, so that gives us one neuron.
好的。嗯，好吧，这样就给了我们一个神经元。
So, one neuron is a logistic regression unit for current purposes.
因此，一个神经元是用于当前目的的逻辑回归单元。
So, crucially what we're wanting to do with neural networks is say, well,
所以，关键的是，我们想要用神经网络做什么就是说，好吧，
why only run one logistic regression,
为什么只进行一次逻辑回归，
why don't we, um,
我们为什么不呢，嗯，
run a whole bunch of logistic regressions at the same time?
同时运行一大堆逻辑回归？
So, you know, here are our inputs and here's our little logistic regression unit, um,
所以，你知道，这是我们的输入，这里是我们的小逻辑回归单元，嗯，
but we could run three logistic regressions at
但我们可以在三处进行三次逻辑回归
the same time or we can run any number of them.
同时或我们可以运行任意数量的它们。
Um, well, that's good but sort of for conventional training of
嗯，嗯，这很好，但有点适合常规训练
a statistical model which sort of have to
一种必须的统计模型
determine for those orange outputs of the logistic regression.
确定逻辑回归的那些橙色输出。
You know, what we're training each of them to try and capture.
你知道，我们正在训练他们每个人尝试捕捉。
We have to have data to predict what they're going to try and capture.
我们必须有数据来预测他们将要尝试和捕获的内容。
And so, the secret of sort of then building bigger neural networks is to say,
因此，建立更大的神经网络的秘密就是说，
we don't actually want to decide ahead of time what
我们实际上并不想提前决定什么
those little orange logistic regressions are trying to capture.
那些小橙色物流回归试图捕捉。
We want the neural network to self-organize,
我们希望神经网络自我组织，
so that those orange logistic regression,
那些橙色逻辑回归，
um, units learn something useful.
嗯，单位学到一些有用的东西。
And well, what is something useful?
那么，什么是有用的？
Well, our idea is to say,
好吧，我们的想法是说，
we do actually have some tasks that we want to do.
我们确实有一些我们想要做的任务。
So, we- we have some tasks that we want to do.
所以，我们 - 我们有一些我们想要做的任务。
So maybe, we want to sort of decide whether a movie review is positive or negative,
所以，也许，我们想要决定电影评论是积极的还是消极的，
something like sentiment analysis or something like that.
像情绪分析或类似的东西。
There is something we want to do at the end of the day.
我们想在一天结束时做些什么。
Um, and we're gonna have, uh,
嗯，我们会的，呃，
logistic regression classifier there telling us positive or negative.
逻辑回归分类器告诉我们正面或负面。
Um, but the inputs to that aren't going to
嗯，但对此的投入是不会的
directly be something like words in the document.
直接就像文档中的单词一样。
They're going to be this intermediate layer of logistic regression units
它们将成为逻辑回归单元的中间层
and we're gonna train this whole thing to minimize our cross entropy loss.
我们将训练这整件事来减少我们的交叉熵损失。
Essentially, what we're going to want to have
基本上，我们希望拥有什么
happen in the back propagation algorithm will do for us,
发生在反向传播算法中会为我们做的，
is to say, you things in the middle,
就是说，你在中间的东西，
it's your job to find some useful way to calculate values from
找到一些有用的计算价值的方法是你的工作
the underlying data such that it'll help our final classifier make a good decision.
基础数据，这将有助于我们的最终分类器做出正确的决定。
I mean in particular, you know,
我的意思是，你知道，
back to this picture, you know.
你知道，回到这张照片。
The final classifier, its just a linear classifier,
最终的分类器，它只是一个线性分类器，
a soft-max or logistic regression.
软最大或逻辑回归。
It's gonna have a line like this.
它会有这样一条线。
But if the intermediate classifiers,
但如果是中间分类器，
they are like a word embedding,
它们就像一个单词嵌入，
they can kind of sort of re-represent the space and shift things around.
它们可以重新代表空间并改变周围的事物。
So, they can learn to shift things around in such a way as
因此，他们可以学会以这样的方式改变现状
you're learning a highly non-linear function of the original input space.
你正在学习原始输入空间的高度非线性函数。
Okay. Um, and so at that point,
好的。嗯，等等，
it's simply a matter of saying,
这只是一个问题，
well, why stop there?
那么，为什么停在那里？
Maybe it gets even better if we put in more layers.
如果我们增加更多层次，也许会变得更好。
And this sort of gets us into the area of deep learning and sort of precisely,
而这种让我们进入深度学习的领域，正是如此，
um, this is, um,
嗯，这是，嗯，
that sort of there was- sort of being three comings of neural networks.
那种神经网络有三种结合。
So the first work in the 50s which is
所以50年代的第一部作品就是
essentially when people had a model of a single neuron
基本上当人们拥有单个神经元的模型时
like this and then only gradually worked out how it
像这样然后才逐渐弄清楚它是怎么回事
related to more conventional statistics than there was.
与更传统的统计数据有关。
Um, the second version of neural networks which we saw the 80s and early 90s, um,
嗯，我们看到了80年代和90年代初的神经网络的第二个版本，嗯，
where people, um, built neural networks like this that had
人们，嗯，建立这样的神经网络
this one hidden layer where a representation could be learned in the middle.
这一个隐藏层，可以在中间学习表示。
But at that time it really wasn't effective.
但当时它确实无效。
Of all people weren't able to build deeper networks and get them to do anything useful.
在所有人中，他们无法建立更深层次的网络并让他们做任何有用的事情。
So you sort of had these neural networks with one hidden layer and so precisely with
所以你有一些神经网络有一个隐藏层，所以精确地使用
research that started in- into deep learning that precisely the motivating question is,
从深入学习开始的研究，恰恰是激励性问题，
um, we believe we'll be able to do even more sophisticated,
嗯，我们相信我们能够做得更复杂，
um, classification for more complex tasks.
嗯，更复杂任务的分类。
Things like speech recognition and image recognition if we could
如果我们能做的话，比如语音识别和图像识别
have a deeper network which will be able to more
有一个更深的网络，将能够更多
effectively learn more sophisticated functions of the input which
有效地学习更复杂的输入功能
will allow us to do things like recognize sounds of a language.
将允许我们做一些事情，如识别语言的声音。
How could we possibly train such a,
我们怎么可能训练这样的，
um, network so they'll work effectively?
嗯，网络，所以他们会有效地工作？
And that's the kind of thing,
这就是那种事，
um, will go on to,
嗯，会继续，
um, more so starting this lecture more so in the next lecture.
嗯，更多的是在下一个讲座中开始这个讲座。
But before we get to there,
但在我们到达之前
um, just to underline it again.
嗯，只是为了再次强调它。
So once we have something like this is our,
所以一旦我们有这样的东西是我们的，
um, layer of a neural network.
嗯，神经网络的一层。
We have a vector of inputs,
我们有一个输入矢量，
we have a vector of outputs and everything is
我们有一个输出向量，一切都是
connected so that we've got this sort of weights along every one of these black lines.
连接，以便我们在这些黑线中的每一条都有这种权重。
And so we can say A1 is you're taking
所以我们可以说A1是你正在服用
weights times each component of X1 and adding a bias term,
权重乘以X1的每个分量并添加偏差项，
um, and then you're going to be running which is sort of
嗯，然后你就要开始运行了
this part and then running it through our non-linearity and that will give us an output.
这部分，然后通过我们的非线性运行它，这将给我们一个输出。
And we're gonna do that for each of A1, A2, and A3.
我们将为A1，A2和A3中的每一个做到这一点。
Um, so again, we can kind of regard A is a vector and we can
嗯，再说一遍，我们可以认为A是一个矢量，我们可以
kind of collapse it into this matrix notation for working out the effects of layers.
将它折叠成这种矩阵表示法来计算层的效果。
The fully connected layers are effectively matrices of weights, um,
完全连接的层是有效的权重矩阵，嗯，
and commonly rewrite them like this where we have a bias term as a vector of bias terms.
并且通常会像这样重写它们，我们将偏差项作为偏差项的向量。
There's sort of a choice there.
那里有一种选择。
You can either have an always on import and then
您可以随时进行导入
the bias terms become part of the weights of a slightly bigger matrix with one extra,
偏差项成为稍微更大的矩阵的权重的一部分，有一个额外的，
uh, one extra either column or row.
呃，一个额外的列或行。
One extra, a- row, right?
一个额外的，一排，对吧？
Or you can just sort of have them separately within those Bs.
或者你可以在这些B中分别拥有它们。
Okay. Um, and then the final note here- right?
好的。嗯，然后最后的说明在这里 - 对吗？
So once we've calculated this part,
所以一旦我们计算了这个部分，
we always put things through non-linearity which is referred to as
我们总是通过非线性来处理事情，这被称为
the activation function and so something like
激活功能等等
the logistic transform I showed earlier is an activation function.
我之前展示的逻辑变换是激活函数。
And this is written as sort of vector in port, um,
这是作为端口中的矢量写的，嗯，
activation function giving a vector output,
激活函数给出矢量输出，
and what this always means is that we apply this function element-wise.
这总是意味着我们在元素方面应用这个功能。
So we're applying the logistic function which is sort of a
所以我们应用的是逻辑函数
naturally a one input one output function like the little graph I showed before.
自然是一个输入一个输出功能，就像我之前展示的小图。
So when we apply that to a vector,
所以当我们将它应用于矢量时，
we apply it to each element of the vector element-wise.
我们将它应用于向量元素的每个元素。
Okay. We will come back very soon to sort of saying
好的。我们很快就会回来说
more about non-linearities and what non-linearities people actually use.
更多关于非线性和人们实际使用的非线性。
Um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
something you might be wondering is well,
你可能想知道的事情很好，
why does he always have these non-linearities
为什么他总是有这些非线性
and say there has to be an f function there?
并说那里必须有一个f函数？
Why don't we just, um,
我们为什么不这样做，嗯，
calculate Z equals WX plus B in one layer and then go
在一层中计算Z等于WX加B然后去
on to another layer that also does Z2 equals W2,
在另一层上，Z2也等于W2，
Z1 plus B and keep on going with layers like that?
Z1加B并继续使用这样的图层？
And there's a very precise reason for that which is if you want
如果你想要的话，有一个非常精确的原因
to have a neural network learn anything interesting,
让神经网络学到任何有趣的东西，
you have to stick in some function F which is
你必须坚持一些功能F.
a non-linear function such as the logistic curve I showed before.
非线性函数，例如我之前显示的逻辑曲线。
And the reason for that is that if you're sort of doing
这样做的原因是，如果你有点干嘛
linear transforms like WX plus B and then W2 Z1 plus B,
线性变换如WX加B然后W2 Z1加B，
W3Z2 plus B and you're doing a sequence of linear transforms.
W3Z2加B，你正在进行一系列线性变换。
Well, multiple linear transforms just composed to become a linear transform, right?
那么，多个线性变换只是组成一个线性变换，对吗？
So one linear transform is rotating and stretching the space somehow and you can
因此，一个线性变换是以某种方式旋转和拉伸空间，你可以
rotate and stretch the space again but the result of
再次旋转和拉伸空间，但结果
that is just one bigger rotate and stretch of the space.
这只是一个更大的旋转和伸展的空间。
So you don't get any extra power for a classifier
所以你没有为分类器获得任何额外的动力
by simply having multiple linear transforms.
通过简单地进行多次线性变换。
But as soon as you stick in almost any kind of non-linearity,
但是只要你坚持几乎任何一种非线性，
then you get additional power.
然后你获得额外的力量。
And so you know in general,
所以你知道，
what we're doing when we're doing deep networks, um,
当我们做深层网络时，我们正在做什么，嗯，
in the middle of them we're not thinking, "Ah,
在他们中间，我们没有想到，“啊，
it's really important to have
拥有它真的很重要
non-linearity thinking about probabilities or something like that."
关于概率的非线性思考或类似的东西。“
Our general picture is well,
我们的总体情况很好，
we want to be able to do effective function approximation or curve fitting.
我们希望能够进行有效的函数逼近或曲线拟合。
We'd like to learn a space like this and we can only do that if we're sort of putting in
我们想要学习这样的空间，如果我们有点投入，我们只能这样做
some non-linearities which allow us to learn these kind of curvy decision, um, patterns.
一些非线性，使我们能够学习这些弯曲的决定，嗯，模式。
And so- so F is used effectively for doing accurate
因此，F有效地用于做准确
[NOISE] fu- function approximation or sort of pattern matching as you go along.
[NOISE]功能近似或类型匹配。
Okay. You are behind already. Um, okay.
好的。你已经落后了。嗯，好的。
So that was the intro to baby neural networks.
这就是婴儿神经网络的介绍。
All good? Any questions?
都好？任何问题？
Yes?
是？
Yeah, like er, feature one and feature
是的，像呃，功能一和功能
four if- if you multiply it together it's highly indicative of like the label Y,
四，如果你将它们相乘，它就像标签Y一样高度指示，
can you get to that product relationship
你能达到那种产品关系吗？
to just say [NOISE] couple of layers that are linear?
只是说[NOISE]几个线性的层？
Um, yes. Good question.
嗯，是的。好问题。
So, in conventional stats,
所以，在传统的统计数据中，
you have your basic input features and when
你有基本的输入功能和时间
people are building something like a logistic regression model by hand,
人们正在手工建立类似逻辑回归模型的东西，
people often say well,
人们经常说得好，
something that's really important for classification is
对分类来说非常重要的东西是
looking at the pair of feature four and feature seven.
看着这对特色四和七特色。
Um, that you know,
嗯，你知道，
if both of those are true at the same time something i-important
如果这两个都是同时真实的东西我很重要
happens and so that's referred to normally in stats as an interaction term,
发生，因此在统计中通常称为交互术语，
and you can by hand a-add interaction terms to your model.
您可以手动为模型添加交互项。
So, essentially a large part of the secret here is having these intermediate layers.
因此，这里的秘密很大一部分就是拥有这些中间层。
They can learn, build interaction terms by themselves.
他们可以自己学习，建立互动条款。
Yeah, so it's sort of, um,
是的，所以它有点，嗯，
automating the search for higher-order terms that you wanna put into your model.
自动搜索您想要放入模型的高阶项。
Okay. I'll go on, other questions?
好的。我会继续，其他问题？
Okay. Um, so um, yeah.
好的。嗯，恩，是的。
So here's a brief little interlude on a teeny bit more of
所以这里有一个简短的小插曲
NLP which is sort of a kind of problem we're gonna to look at for a moment.
NLP这是一种我们暂时会看到的问题。
So this is the task of named entity recognition that I very briefly mentioned last time.
所以这是我上次非常简要提到的命名实体识别的任务。
So, um, if we have some text,
那么，嗯，如果我们有一些文字，
wait, it isn't appearing here.
等等，它没有出现在这里。
Okay. Uh, okay.
好的。呃，好的。
If we have some text,
如果我们有一些文字，
something that in all sorts of places people want to do
在人们想要做的各种各样的地方
is I'd like to find the names of things that are mentioned.
我想找到提到的东西的名字。
Um and then normally, as well as,
嗯，然后通常，以及，
finding the names of things you'd actually like to classify them,
找到你真正喜欢的东西的名字，
say it's like to say some of them are organizations,
说这就像是说其中一些是组织，
some of them are people,
其中一些是人，
um, some of them are places.
嗯，其中一些是地方。
And so you know this has lots of uses, you know,
所以你知道这有很多用途，你知道，
people like to track mentions of companies and
人们喜欢跟踪公司和公司的提及
people and newspapers and things like that.
人和报纸等等。
Um, people when they do question-answering that a lot of the time the answers
嗯，人们在做问题时很多时候回答问题
to questions are what we call named entities the names of people,
问题就是我们称之为命名实体的名字，
locations, organizations, pop songs,
地点，组织，流行歌曲，
movie names all of those kind of things are named entities.
电影名称所有这些东西都是命名实体。
Um, and if you want to sort of start
嗯，如果你想开始
building up a knowledge base automatically from a lot of text,
从大量文本中自动构建知识库，
well, what you normally wanna do is get out
好吧，你通常想做的就是出去
the named entities and get out relations between them.
命名实体并获得它们之间的关系。
So this is a common task.
所以这是一项常见的任务。
So, how can we go about doing that?
那么，我们该怎么做呢？
And a common way of doing that is to say well,
这样做的一种常见方式就是说，
we're going to go through the words one at a time
我们将逐个完成一个单词
and they're gonna be words that are in a context just like they were for word to deck,
而且他们会成为一种语境，就像他们的言语一样，
and what we're gonna do is run a classifier and we're going to assign them a class.
而我们要做的就是运行一个分类器，我们将为它们分配一个类。
So we're gonna say first word is organization,
所以我们要说第一个词是组织，
second word is organization,
第二个词是组织，
third word isn't a named entity,
第三个字不是命名实体，
fourth word is a person,
第四个字是一个人，
fifth word is a person and continue down.
第五个字是一个人并继续下去。
So in running a classification of a word within
所以在运行一个单词的分类
a position in the text so it's got surrounding words around it.
文本中的一个位置，所以它周围有周围的单词。
Um and so to say what the entities are
嗯，所以说实体是什么
many entities are multi-word terms and so the simplest thing you can
许多实体都是多字词，所以最简单的事情就是你
imagine doing is just say we'll take the sequence that are all classified the
想象做的只是说我们将采取所有分类的序列
same and call that the e-entity Shen Guofang or something like that.
同样称之为电子实体沉国放之类的东西。
There's a reason why that's slightly defective and so
有一个原因，那就是有点缺陷等等
what people often use is that BIO encoding,
人们经常使用的是BIO编码，
um, that I show on the right but I'll just gonna run ahead and not do that now.
嗯，我在右边展示，但我会跑到前面而不是现在就这样做。
Um so, it might seem at first that named entity recognition is trivial because you know,
嗯，起初看起来可能认为实体识别是微不足道的，因为你知道，
you have company names Google and Facebook are company names.
你有公司名称谷歌和Facebook是公司名称。
And whenever you see Google or Facebook you just say company and how could you be wrong?
每当你看到谷歌或Facebook时，你只是说公司，你怎么会错？
But in practice, there's a lot of subtlety and it's
但在实践中，有很多微妙之处
easy to be wrong in named entity recognition.
在命名实体识别中容易出错。
So this is sort of just some of the hard cases.
所以这只是一些困难的案例。
So it's often hard to work out the boundaries of an entity.
因此，通常很难找出实体的边界。
So in this sentence,
所以在这句话中，
First National Bank don-donates two vans to Future School of Fort Smith.
第一国民银行向史密斯堡未来学校捐赠两辆面包车。
So, there's presumably the name of a bank there but is it National Bank and the first is
所以，可能有一家银行的名称，但它是国家银行，第一个是
just the first word of a sentence which is cap-capitalized
只是一个限额的句子的第一个单词
like first she ordered some food or something.
就像她先点一些食物一样。
So kind of unclear what it is.
所以有点不清楚它是什么。
Sometimes it's hard to know whether something's an entity at all.
有时很难知道某些东西是否是一个实体。
So at the end of this sentence is Future School the name of
所以在这句话的最后是Future School的名字
some exciting kind of 21st-century school or is it
一些令人兴奋的21世纪学校或是它
just meaning it's a future school that's gonna be built in this town, right?
只是意味着这是一个未来的学校，将在这个城镇建造，对吧？
Is it an entity or not at all?
它是一个实体还是根本没有？
Working out the class of an entity is often difficult so to find out more
制定一个实体的类通常很困难，以便找到更多
about Zig Ziglar and read features by what class is Zig Ziglar?
关于Zig Ziglar和读Zig Ziglar这个类的功能？
Kinda hard to tell if you don't know.
如果你不知道，有点难以分辨。
Um, it's actually a person's name, um,
嗯，这实际上是一个人的名字，嗯，
and there are various entities that are ambiguous, right?
并且有各种各样的实体是模棱两可的，对吧？
So Charles Schwab in text is
所以Charles Schwab在文中是
90% of the time an organization name because there's Charles Schwab Brokerage.
组织名称的90％是因为有Charles Schwab Brokerage。
Um, but in this particular sentence here,
嗯，但在这个特别的句子里，
in Woodside where Larry Ellison and
在伍德赛德拉里埃里森和
Charles Schwab can live discreetly among wooded estates,
查尔斯施瓦布可以在树木繁茂的庄园中谨慎地生活，
that is then a reference to Charles Schwab the person.
那就是这个人对查尔斯施瓦布的提及。
So there's sort of a fair bit of understanding variously that's needed to get it right.
因此，为了做到这一点，需要进行各种各样的理解。
Okay. Um, so what are we gonna do with that?
好的。嗯，那我们要做什么呢？
And so this suggests, um,
所以这表明，嗯，
what we wanna do is build classifiers for language that work inside a context.
我们想要做的是为在上下文中工作的语言构建分类器。
Um, so you know, in general,
嗯，所以你知道，一般来说，
it's not very interesting classifying a word
分类一个单词并不是很有趣
outside a context we don't actually do that much in NLP.
在上下文之外，我们实际上并没有在NLP中做那么多。
Um, but once you're in a context, um,
嗯，但是一旦你处在一个环境中，嗯，
then it's interesting to do and named entity recognition
那么做和命名实体识别很有意思
is one case there are lots of other places that comes up.
是一个案例，有很多其他地方出现。
I mean, here's a slightly cool one,
我的意思是，这里有点酷，
that there are some words that can mean
有一些词可能意味着
themselves and their opposite at the same time, right?
他们自己和他们的对立面同时对吧？
So to sanction something can either mean to allow
因此，制裁某事可能意味着允许
something or it can mean to punish people who do
某事或它可能意味着惩罚做的人
things or to seed something can either mean to plant seeds
事物或种子的东西可能意味着种植种子
and things that you're seeding the soil or it can
以及你正在播种土壤的东西
take seeds out of something like a watermelon, right?
从西瓜这样的东西中取出种子，对吧？
You just need to know the context as to which it is.
您只需要了解它的背景。
Okay. So, that suggests the tasks that we can classify a word
好的。所以，这表明我们可以对一个单词进行分类的任务
in its context of neighboring words and any has an example of that.
在其相邻单词的上下文中，任何一个都有这样的例子。
And the question is how might we do that?
问题是我们如何做到这一点？
And a very simple way to do it might be to say, "Well,
一个非常简单的方法可能就是说，“嗯，
we have a bunch of words in a row
我们有一堆连续的单词
which each have a word vector from something like word to vec.
每个人都有一个单词向量，从单词到vec。
Um, maybe we could just average
嗯，也许我们可以平均
those word vectors and then classify the resulting vector.
那些单词向量然后对结果向量进行分类。
The problem is that doesn't work very well because you lose position information.
问题是，由于丢失了位置信息，因此效果不佳。
You don't actually know anymore which of
你实际上不知道哪个
those word vectors is the one that you're meant to be classifying.
那些单词向量是你要分类的那个。
So, a simple way to do better than that is to say,
所以，一个比这更好的简单方法就是说，
"Well, why didn't we make a big vector of a word window?"
“好吧，为什么我们没有制作一个文字窗口的大矢量？”
So, here are words and they each have a word vector,
所以，这里是单词，每个都有一个单词向量，
and so to classify the middle word in the context of here plus or minus two words,
所以要在这里加上或减去两个单词的上下文中对中间词进行分类，
we're simply going to concatenate these five vectors together and say now we have
我们只是简单地将这五个向量连接在一起并说现在我们有
a bigger vector and let's build a classifier over that vector.
一个更大的向量，让我们在该向量上构建一个分类器。
So, we're classifying this x window which is then a vector in,
所以，我们将这个x窗口分类，然后是一个向量，
ah, 5D if we're using D dimensional word vectors.
啊，5D如果我们使用D维词向量。
We can do that um in the kind of way that we did previously which is, um,
我们可以用我们之前做过的那种方式做到这一点，嗯，
that we could say, "Okay,
我们可以说，“好的，
for that big vector we're going to learn w weights
对于那个大矢量，我们将学习w权重
and we're put- gonna put it through a softmax classifier,
我们会把它放到softmax分类器中，
and then we're going to do the decisions."
然后我们将做出决定。“
Um, that's a perfectly good way to do things and,
嗯，这是一个非常好的做事方式，
um, for the purpose of it.
嗯，为了它的目的。
What I want to get to in the last part of this is to
我想在最后一部分得到的是
start looking at my, um, matrix calculus.
开始看我的，嗯，矩阵演算。
And you know we could use this model and do
你知道我们可以使用这个模型
a classifier and learn the weights of it and indeed, um,
一个分类器，并学习它的重量，实际上，嗯，
for the handout on the website that we suggest you look at it does
对于我们建议你看看它的网站上的讲义
do it with a softmax classifier of precisely this kind.
使用这种类似的softmax分类器来做到这一点。
Um, but for the example I do in class I try to make it a bit simpler.
嗯，但是我在课堂上做的例子我试着让它更简单一些。
Um, and I've wanted to do this I think very quickly because I'm fast running out of time.
嗯，我想要这么做我想很快，因为我快速耗尽时间。
So, one of the famous early papers of neural NLP, um,
那么，神经NLP的着名早期论文之一，嗯，
was this paper by Collobert and Weston which was first
这是Collobert和Weston的第一篇论文
an ICML paper in 2008 which actually just a couple of weeks ago,
2008年的ICML论文，实际上就在几周前，
um, won the ICML 2018 test of time award.
嗯，赢得了ICML 2018年度时间奖测试。
Um, and then there's a more recent journal version of it 2011.
嗯，然后是2011年的最新期刊版本。
And um, they use this idea of
嗯，他们使用这个想法
window classification to assign classes like named entities,
窗口分类，用于分配命名实体等类，
ti- to words in context, um,
在上下文中的话，嗯，
but they did it in a slightly different way.
但他们以稍微不同的方式做到了。
So, what they said is, "Well,
所以，他们说的是，“嗯，
we've got these windows and this is one with the, um,
我们有这些窗户，这是一个与，嗯，
location named entity in the middle and
位于中间的位置命名实体
this is one without a location entity in the middle.
这是一个中间没有位置实体的人。
So, what we want to do is have a system that returns a score,
所以，我们想做的是有一个返回分数的系统，
and it should return a high score just as a real number in this case and
在这种情况下，它应该返回一个高分，就像一个实数一样
it can should return a low score if it- if there isn't,
如果没有，它应该返回低分，如果没有，
ah, location name in the middle of the window in this case.
啊，在这种情况下窗口中间的位置名称。
So, explicitly the model just return the score.
所以，明确地说模型只返回得分。
So, if you had the top level of your neural network a,
所以，如果你拥有神经网络的顶级水平，
and you just then dot product did with a vector u,
然后你就点了产品做了矢量你，
you then kind of with that final dot product,
那么你最后的点产品，
you just return a real number.
你只需要返回一个实数。
They use that as the basis of their classifier.
他们将其作为分类器的基础。
So in full glory,
如此充满荣耀，
what you had is you had this window of words,
你有什么，你有这个窗口，
you looked up a word vector for each word, you then, um,
你抬起每个单词的单词向量，然后你，嗯，
multiplied that the, the- well you
乘以你，好吧
concatenated the word vectors for the window.
连接窗口的单词向量。
You multiplied them by a matrix and edited a bias to get
您将它们乘以矩阵并编辑偏差得到
a second hidden layer which is a and then you multiply that by
第二个隐藏层是a，然后你乘以
a final vector and that gave you a score for the window and you
一个最终的矢量，并给你一个窗口和你的分数
wanted the score to be large if it was the location and small,
想要得分很大，如果它是位置和小，
if it wasn't a location.
如果它不是一个位置。
So, in this sort of pretend example where we have four dimensional word vectors,
所以，在这种我们有四维单词向量的假装示例中，
um, that's meaning you know for the window,
嗯，这意味着你知道窗户，
this is a 20 x 1 vector.
这是一个20 x 1的向量。
Um, for calculating the next hidden layer we've
嗯，我们计算下一个隐藏层
got an 8 by 20 matrix plus the bias vector.
得到一个8乘20矩阵加偏置向量。
Then, we've got this sort of 8-dimensional second hidden layer
然后，我们有了这种8维第二隐藏层
and then we are computing a final real number.
然后我们计算最终的实数。
Okay. Um, and so crucially this is an example of what the question was about.
好的。嗯，所以关键是这是问题的一个例子。
Um, we've put in this extra layer here, right?
嗯，我们在这里加上这个额外的层，对吗？
We could have just said here's a word vector,
我们刚才可以说这是一个单词向量，
a big word vector of, of context.
上下文的大词矢量。
Let's just stick a softmax or
让我们坚持使用softmax或
logistic classification on top to say yes or no for location.
最上面的逻辑分类，对位置说是或否。
But by putting in that extra hidden layer
但是通过添加额外的隐藏层
precisely this extra hidden layer can calculate
正是这个额外的隐藏层可以计算出来
non-linear interactions between the input word vectors.
输入词向量之间的非线性相互作用。
So, it can calculate things like if
所以，它可以计算像if这样的东西
the first word is a word like museum and the second and the second
第一个词是像博物馆这样的词，第二个词和第二个词
was a word like the preposition in or
是一个像介词中的词或
around then that's a very good signal that this should be,
在那附近，这是一个非常好的信号，这应该是，
ah, location in the middle position of the window.
啊，位置在窗口的中间位置。
So, extra layers of a neural network let us calculate
因此，神经网络的额外层让我们计算
these kind of interaction terms between our basic features.
我们的基本功能之间的这种互动术语。
Okay. Um, so there's
好的。嗯，所以有
a few more slides here that sort of go through the details of their model,
这里有一些幻灯片，它们会详细介绍他们的模型，
but I'm gonna just skip those for now because I'm a little bit behind.
但是我现在要跳过那些因为我有点落后了。
And at the end of it we've just got this score.
最后我们得到了这个分数。
So this is our model which is the one that I just outlined where we're
所以这就是我们刚才概述的那个模型
calculating the score and we're wanting a big score, um, for location.
计算得分，我们想要一个大分，嗯，位置。
And so, what we're gonna want to do is consider, um,
所以，我们要做的就是考虑，嗯，
how we can use this model,
我们如何使用这个模型，
um, to learn, um,
嗯，要学习，嗯，
our parameters in a neural network.
我们在神经网络中的参数。
Um, so in particular,
嗯，特别是，
remember it's the same story we've had before.
记住这是我们以前的故事。
We had a loss function J,
我们有一个损失函数J，
and we're wanting to work out, um,
我们想要锻炼，嗯，
the gradient with respect to our current theta parameters of the loss function.
相对于我们当前损失函数的θ参数的梯度。
Then, we want to sort of subtract a little multiple of that, um,
那么，我们想减去那个的一点点，嗯，
given by the learning rate from our current parameters to get updated parameters,
根据我们当前参数的学习率给出更新参数，
and if we repeatedly do then stochastic
如果我们反复做那么随机
gradient descent we'll have better and better parameters
梯度下降我们会有更好更好的参数
which give higher probability to the things
这给了事物更高的概率
that we're actually observing in our training data.
我们实际上正在观察我们的训练数据。
So, the thing we want to know is, well,
所以，我们想知道的是，嗯，
in general how can we do this um,
一般来说我们怎么能这样做，
differentiation and work out the gradient of our loss function?
区分并计算出我们的损失函数的梯度？
And so, I sort of wanted to sort of this the remaining time in this lecture,
所以，我有点想把这个剩下的时间放在这个讲座中，
um, go through how we can do that by hand, um,
嗯，看看我们怎么能用手做，嗯，
using math and then that'll lead into sort of
使用数学，那将导致一些
discussing and more generally the backpropagation algorithm,
讨论，更一般地说，反向传播算法，
um, for the next one.
嗯，为下一个。
Okay. So, if we're doing um,
好的。那么，如果我们这样做，
gradients by hand well we're doing multi-variable calculus, multi-variable derivatives.
手动渐变我们正在做多变量微积分，多变量导数。
But in particular normally the most useful way to think about this is as doing
但特别是通常最有用的思考方式就是这样做
matrix calculus which means we're directly working with
矩阵演算意味着我们正在直接使用
vectors and matrices to work out our gradients,
矢量和矩阵来计算我们的渐变，
and that that's normally sort of much faster and more convenient for
而这通常更快，更方便
summarizing our neural network layers than trying to do it in a non vectorized way.
总结我们的神经网络层而不是尝试以非矢量化方式进行。
But that doesn't mean that's the only way to do it.
但这并不意味着这是唯一的方法。
If you're sort of confused about what's going on,
如果你对发生的事情感到困惑，
sometimes thinking it through in
有时候会考虑进去
the non vectorized way can be a better way to understand what's going on and,
非矢量化方式可以更好地了解正在发生的事情，
um, make more progress.
嗯，取得更多进展。
So, like when, um,
所以，就像什么时候一样，嗯，
last time I did the word2vec um
上次我做了word2vec嗯
derivatives when I was writing too small on that board,
当我在那块板上写得太小时，衍生品，
sorry, um, that was doing it in a non vectorized way of working out the weights,
对不起，嗯，那是用非矢量化的方法来计算权重，
talking about them individually.
单独谈论他们。
Um, but here we're going to do it with,
嗯，但是我们要在这里做，
um, vectors and matrices.
嗯，矢量和矩阵。
And again, look for the lecture notes to cover this material in more detail.
再次，查看讲义以更详细地介绍这些材料。
In particular, so that no one misses it.
特别是，没有人会错过它。
Um, let me just clarify what I mean by lecture notes.
嗯，让我通过讲义来澄清我的意思。
So, if you look at the course syllabus on the left-hand column, um,
所以，如果你看一下左栏的课程大纲，嗯，
there's the slides that you can download and,
你可以下载幻灯片，
on straight under the slides,
在幻灯片的正下方，
it says lecture notes.
它说讲义。
That's what I'm meaning by the lecture notes.
这就是我在讲义中所说的意思。
In the- in the middle column it then has some readings and
在中间列中，它有一些读数和
actually there are some diffe- additional things there that cover similar material.
实际上，那里有一些不同的东西，涵盖类似的材料。
Um, so there's, um,
嗯，所以，嗯，
so there's they might be helpful as well.
所以他们也可能会有所帮助。
But first the thing that's closest to what I'm about to present,
但首先是最接近我要呈现的东西，
it's the lecture notes that appear immediately under the slides link.
它是立即出现在幻灯片链接下的讲义。
Okay. Um, so my hope here, um,
好的。嗯，我的希望在这里，嗯，
my hope here is the following: Um,
我的希望如下：嗯，
if you can't remembered how to do single variable calculus,
如果你不记得如何做单变量微积分，
sorry you're basically sunken and might as well leave now.
对不起，你基本上是沉没的，不妨现在离开。
Um, [LAUGHTER] I'm assuming you know how to do
嗯，[笑声]我假设你知道怎么做
single-variable calculus and I'm assuming you know what a um a vector and a matrix is.
单变量微积分，我假设你知道什么是矢量和矩阵。
Um, but you know, um,
嗯，但是你知道，嗯，
I sort of hope that even if you never
我希望即使你永远也不会
did multi-variable calculus or you can't remember any of it,
做了多变量微积分，或者你不记得任何一个，
it's sort of for what we have to do here,
这是我们在这里必须做的事情，
not that hard and you can do it.
没那么难，你可以做到。
So, here's what, um, what you do.
那么，这就是你所做的。
Um, all right.
嗯，好的。
So, if we have a simple function f of x equals x cubed, right.
所以，如果我们有一个简单的函数f，x等于x立方，对。
Its gradient, um, and so the gradient is the slope, right?
它的渐变，嗯，渐变是斜率，对吗？
Saying how steep or shallow is the slope of something,
说某事的斜率有多么陡峭或浅浅，
and then when we and also saw the direction of slope when we go into multiple dimensions.
然后当我们进入多个维度时，我们也看到了斜率的方向。
Um, its gradient is just as derivatives.
嗯，它的梯度就像衍生物一样。
So, its derivative is 3x squared.
因此，它的衍生物是3倍平方。
Um, so if you're at the point x equals 3, that you know,
嗯，所以，如果你在x等于3，你知道，
the sort of this 27 of sloppiness,
这种27的邋,,
um, is very steep.
嗯，非常陡峭。
Okay. So well, what if we have a function with one output but now it has many inputs?
好的。那么，如果我们有一个输出功能，但现在它有很多输入怎么办？
Um, so that we're sort of doing that sort of, um,
嗯，这样我们就是这样做的，嗯，
function that was like the dot products where we're doing the sort of the UTV or WTX,
功能，就像我们正在做UTV或WTX那样的点积，
um, to calculate a value.
嗯，计算一个值。
Well, then what we're gonna calculate is
好吧，那么我们要计算的是
a gradient which is a vector of partial derivatives with respect to each input.
梯度，它是关于每个输入的偏导数的向量。
So, you take, um,
所以，你拿，嗯，
the slope of the function as you change x1,
更改x1时函数的斜率，
the slope of the function as you change x2 through the slope of the, ah,
当你改变x2的斜率时，函数的斜率啊，
function as you change xn and each of these you can just calculate as if you were doing
当你改变xn时你会发挥作用，你可以像计算每一个一样进行计算
single variable calculus and you just put them all in a vector and
单变量微积分，你只需将它们全部放在矢量中
that's then giving you the gradient and then the gradient and multi-dimensional,
然后给你渐变，然后渐变和多维，
um, spaces then giving you the direction and slope of a sort of
嗯，空间然后给你一种方向和斜率
a surface that touches your multi-dimensional, um, f function.
一个接触你的多维，嗯，f函数的表面。
Okay. So that's getting a bit scarier,
好的。所以这有点可怕，
but it gets a little bit scarier than that
但它比那更可怕
because if we have a neutral network layer, um,
因为如果我们有一个中立的网络层，嗯，
we then have a function which will have n inputs,
然后我们有一个有n个输入的函数，
which are the input neurons,
哪些是输入神经元，
and it will have m outputs.
它将有m个输出。
So if that's the case, um,
如果是这样的话，嗯，
you then have a matrix of partial derivatives which is referred to as the Jacobian.
然后你有一个偏导数矩阵，称为雅可比矩阵。
So in the Jacobian, um,
所以雅各比派，嗯，
you're sort of taking these partial derivatives, um,
你有点拿这些偏导数，嗯，
with respect to each, um,
关于每一个，嗯，
output along the rows and with respect to each input down the columns.
沿着行输出并相对于列下的每个输入。
And so you're getting these m by n partial derivatives,
因此，您可以通过n个偏导数得到这些，
considering every combination of an output and an input.
考虑输出和输入的每种组合。
Um, but again, you can fill in every cell of this matrix
嗯，但同样，你可以填写这个矩阵的每个单元格
just by doing single-variable calculus provided you don't get yourself confused.
只需通过单变量微积分，只要你不要让自己感到困惑。
Okay. Um, then we already saw when we were doing word2vec,
好的。嗯，那时我们已经看到我们在做word2vec了，
that sort of a central tool that we have to use to work out,
那种我们必须用来解决的核心工具，
um, to work out, um,
嗯，锻炼，嗯，
our derivatives of something like
我们的衍生品之类的
a neural network model is we have
我们有一个神经网络模型
a sequence of functions that we run up one after another.
我们一个接一个地运行的一系列功能。
So, um, in a neural network you're sort of
所以，嗯，在一个神经网络中，你有点像
running a sequence of functions one after another.
一个接一个地运行一系列功能。
So we have to use, um,
所以我们必须使用，嗯，
the chain rule to work out derivatives when we compose functions.
在我们撰写函数时计算导数的链式规则。
So if we have one variable function, so we have,
所以，如果我们有一个变量函数，那么我们有，
um, C equals 3y and y equals x squared.
嗯，C等于3y，y等于x平方。
If we want to work out, um,
如果我们想要锻炼，嗯，
the derivative of z with respect to x,
z相对于x的导数，
we say, aha, that's a composition of two functions.
我们说，啊哈，这是两个功能的组合。
So I use the chain rule.
所以我使用链规则。
And so that means what I do is I multiply, um, the derivative.
所以这就意味着我所做的就是乘法，嗯，衍生物。
So I take, um, dz/dy.
所以我接受，嗯，dz / dy。
So that's 2x, um,
那是2x，嗯，
wait, [NOISE] Sorry, I said that wrong, right?
等等，[NOISE]对不起，我说错了，对吧？
Is my example wrong?
我的例子错了吗？
Oh yeah, its right, dz/dy.
哦是的，它的权利，dz / dy。
So yeah, dz/dy is just three.
所以是的，dz / dy只有三个。
That's, right, that's the derivative of the top line,
那是，对，这是顶线的衍生物，
and then dy/dx is 2x.
然后dy / dx是2x。
And I multiply those together and I get the answer, um,
我将它们相乘，我得到了答案，嗯，
that the derivative of z with respect to x is 6x.
z相对于x的导数是6x。
Okay. Um, this bit then gets a little bit freakier, but it's true.
好的。嗯，这一点变得有点怪，但这是真的。
If you have lots of variables at once,
如果你一次有很多变量，
you simply multiply the Jacobians and you get the right answer.
你只需乘以雅各比人就可以得到正确的答案。
So if we're now imagining our neural net,
所以，如果我们现在想象我们的神经网络，
well sort of, this is our typical neural net right?
那么，这是我们典型的神经网络吗？
So we're doing the neural net layer where we have
所以我们正在做我们所拥有的神经网络层
our weight matrix multiplied their input vector plus,
我们的权重矩阵乘以它们的输入向量加，
um, the bias, and then we're putting it through a non-linearity.
嗯，偏见，然后我们通过非线性。
And then if we want to know what's the partials of h with respect to x,
然后如果我们想知道关于x的h的部分是什么，
we just say, huh, it's a function composition.
我们只是说，呵呵，这是一个功能组合。
So this is easy to do.
所以这很容易做到。
We work out our first Jacobian,
我们制作了我们的第一个雅可比人，
which is the partials of h with respect to z,
这是h相对于z的部分，
and then we just multiply it by the partials of z with respect to x,
然后我们将它乘以z相对于x的部分，
and we get the right answer.
我们得到了正确的答案。
Um, easy.
嗯，很简单。
Um, so here's sort of um
嗯，所以这里有点嗯
an example Jacobian which is a special case that comes up a lot.
Jacobian的一个例子，这是一个很常见的特殊情况。
Um, so it's just good to realize this one which we'll see with our neural net.
嗯，所以我们用神经网络看到的这个很好。
So well one of the things that we have are these element-wise activation function.
我们所拥有的一件事就是这些元素激活功能。
So we have h equals f of z.
所以我们有h等于z的f。
So, um, what is the, um,
那么，嗯，这是什么，嗯，
partial derivative of h with respect to z. Um,
h的偏导数相对于z。嗯，
well the thing- remember that we sort of apply this element-wise.
好的东西 - 记住，我们有点应用这个元素。
So we're actually saying hi equals f of zi.
所以我们实际上说hi等于zi的f。
So, you know, formally this function has n inputs and n outputs,
所以，你知道，这个函数正式有n个输入和n个输出，
so it's partial derivatives are going to be an n by n Jacobian.
所以它的偏导数将成为雅各比亚的n。
But if we think about what's happening there,
但如果我们考虑那里发生的事情，
um, what we're actually going to find is, sort of,
嗯，我们实际上会发现的是，有点像，
when we're working out the terms of this so we're working out,
当我们计算出这个条款时，我们正在努力，
how does f of zi change as you change zj?
当你改变zj时，zi如何改变？
Well, if j is not equal to i,
好吧，如果j不等于i，
it's gonna make no difference at all, right?
它根本没有任何区别，对吧？
So if my f function is something like putting it through
所以，如果我的f函数就像通过它一样
the logistic function or anything else absolute valuing a number,
逻辑函数或其他任何绝对重要的数字，
it's gonna make no difference for the calculation of f of zi
对于zi的f的计算，它没有任何区别
if I chains zj because it's just not in the equation.
如果我链zj因为它不在等式中。
And so, therefore, the only terms that are actually going to occur
因此，实际上将会发生的唯一条款
and be non-zero are the terms where i equals j.
并且非零是i等于j的项。
So for working out these partial derivatives if i does not equal j, um, it's zero.
因此，如果我不等于j，那么为了计算出这些偏导数，它就是零。
If i does equal j,
如果我确实等于j，
then we have to work out a single-variable calculus.
那么我们必须计算出单变量微积分。
What's the derivative, um,
什么是衍生物，嗯，
of the, um, activation function, um,
嗯，激活功能，嗯，
for- and so this is what,
因为 - 这就是，
a um, Jacobian looks like for an activation function.
嗯，Jacobian看起来像激活功能。
It's a diagonal matrix.
这是一个对角矩阵。
Everything else is zero,
其他一切都是零，
and we thought this activation function,
我们认为这个激活功能，
we work out its derivative,
我们计算出它的衍生物，
and then we calculate that for the difference, um,
然后我们计算差异，嗯，
we have it for the different kind of um, zi values.
我们有不同类型的um，zi值。
Okay. Um, so that's a,
好的。嗯，这是一个，
um, Jacobians for an activation function.
嗯，Jacobians的激活功能。
What are the other main cases,
还有哪些主要案例，
uh, that we need for a neural network?
呃，我们需要神经网络吗？
And these I'll go in through a little bit more slowly in the same lecture notes.
而这些我将在同一个讲义中慢慢地进入。
But they're kind of similar to what we saw in the very first class.
但它们与我们在第一堂课中所看到的相似。
So if we are wanting to work out the partial derivatives of wx plus b with respect to x,
因此，如果我们想要计算wx加b的偏导数x，
um, what we get is w. Um,
嗯，我们得到的是w。嗯，
and if we want to work out the partial derivative of wx plus b with respect to b,
如果我们想要计算wx加b的偏导数b，
um, that means that we get an identity matrix because b is sort of like a 1b, right?
嗯，这意味着我们得到一个单位矩阵，因为b有点像1b，对吧？
It's this almost always on vector,
这几乎总是在矢量上，
so you're just getting the ones coming out to preserve the b. Um,
所以你只是把那些出来保存b。嗯，
this was the case, um,
是这样的，嗯，
that we saw, um,
我们看到了，嗯，
when we were doing the word vectors.
当我们做单词向量时。
That if you have a vector dot product of u and h and you say,
如果你有一个u和h的矢量点积，你说，
what's the partial derivatives of that with respect to u,
关于你的那部分衍生物是什么，
then you get out h transpose.
然后你出去转置。
Um, if you haven't seen those before,
嗯，如果你之前没见过，
um, look at the lecture notes handouts, um,
嗯，看看讲义上的讲义，嗯，
and see if you can compute them and they make sense at home, um,
并看看你是否可以计算它们，它们在家里有意义，嗯，
but for the moment we're gonna believe those and use those to
但是目前我们会相信那些并使用它们
see how we can then work out derivatives inside the neural network.
看看我们如何在神经网络中找出衍生物。
Okay. So here's the same neural network we saw before.
好的。所以这是我们之前看到的相同的神经网络。
So we have a window of words,
所以我们有一个词窗口，
we're looking at word vectors,
我们正在寻找单词向量，
we're putting it through a hidden layer,
我们把它穿过隐藏层，
and then we're just doing a vector modal, um,
然后我们只是做一个矢量模态，嗯，
vector dot product, you get this final score.
矢量点积，你得到这个最终得分。
And so, what we [NOISE] want to do to be able to train our neural network,
所以，我们[NOISE]希望能够训练我们的神经网络，
is we want to find out how- how s changes depending on all the parameters of the model.
我们是否想要了解如何根据模型的所有参数进行更改。
The x, the w, the b, the u. Um,
x，w，b，u。嗯，
and so we want to work out partial derivatives of S with respect
所以我们想要尊重S的偏导数
to each of those because we can then work out okay if you move b up,
对于每一个，因为如果你向上移动b，我们可以做得很好
um, the score gets better,
嗯，分数越来越好，
which is good if it's actually a plus in the middle,
如果它实际上是中间的加号，这是好的，
and therefore we'll want to nudge up,
因此我们想要轻推，
um, elements of b appropriately.
嗯，b的元素恰当。
Okay, um, and so I'm just doing the gradient with
好的，嗯，所以我只是做渐变
respect to the score here and I skipped over those couple of slides.
尊重这里的分数，我跳过了那几张幻灯片。
Um, so if you're just, sort of,
嗯，如果你只是，有点像，
staring at this picture and say, well,
盯着这张照片说，好吧，
how do I work out the partial derivative of s with respect to b?
我如何计算出关于b的s的偏导数？
Um, probably it doesn't look obvious.
嗯，可能看起来并不明显。
So the first thing here that you want to do is sort of break up
所以你要做的第一件事就是分手
the eq- equations into simple pieces that compose together, right?
将方程式组合成简单的组合，对吧？
So you have the input x,
所以你有输入x，
and then that goes into z equals wx plus b,
然后进入z等于wx加b，
and then you compose that with the next thing.
然后你用下一个东西组成。
So h equals f of z, our activation function,
所以h等于z，我们的激活函数，
and then this h goes into the next thing of s equals uTh.
然后这个h进入下一个等于你的东西。
So we've got these sequence of functions.
所以我们有这些功能序列。
And pretty much you want to break things up as much as you can.
而且你想要尽可能多地分解。
I mean, I could have broken this up even further.
我的意思是，我可以进一步打破这个。
I could have said z1 equals wx,
我可以说z1等于wx，
z equals z1 plus b. Um,
z等于z1加b。嗯，
it turns out um,
事实证明，嗯，
but if you've just got things added and subtracted,
但是如果你只是添加和减少了东西，
you can sort of do that in one step because that sort of pathway separating the,
你可以一步到位，因为这种途径分开了，
when doing the derivatives,
在做衍生品时，
but sort of anything else that composes together you want to pull it out for the pieces.
但是，除了组合在一起的任何其他东西，你想把它拉出来。
Okay. So now our neural net is doing a sequence of function compositions.
好的。所以现在我们的神经网络正在做一系列功能组合。
And when we say, okay,
当我们说，好吧，
we know how to do that, the chain rule.
我们知道如何做到这一点，链条规则。
So if you wanna work out the partials of s with respect to b,
所以如果你想弄清楚关于b的部分s，
it's just going to be the product of the derivatives of each step along the way.
它将成为沿途每一步的衍生产品。
So it's gonna be um the partial of s with respect to h times h with
因此，对于h次h而言，它将是部分s
respect to z times z with respect to b and that will give us the right answer.
尊重关于b的z次z，这将给我们正确的答案。
So then all we have to do is actually compute that.
那么我们所要做的就是实际计算。
Um, so, I think this just sort of
嗯，所以，我认为这只是一种
shows okay we're taking the partials of each step of that composition.
显示我们正在考虑该组合的每一步的部分内容。
Okay. So now we want to compute that.
好的。所以现在我们要计算它。
And so this is where I'm going to sort of use the Jacobians that I
所以这就是我要使用雅各比人的地方
sort of asserted without much proof on the preceding slide.
在上一张幻灯片中没有太多证据的断言。
Okay. So first of all um we have ds/dh.
好的。首先，我们有ds / dh。
Well, that's just the dot product of two vectors.
嗯，这只是两个向量的点积。
So the um, the Jacobian for that is just h transpose.
所以嗯，Jacobian就是这个转座。
Okay, that's a start.
好的，这是一个开始。
Then we have um h equals f of z.
然后我们将u等于z的f。
Well, that's the activation function.
好吧，这就是激活功能。
So the um Jacobian of that is
所以雅各比亚的那个是
this diagonal matrix made of the element wise um derivative of the function
这个对角矩阵由元素的um函数的导数组成
f. And then we have the partial of z
F。然后我们有部分z
with respect to b and that's the bit that comes out as the identity matrix.
关于b，这是作为单位矩阵出现的位。
And so that's then giving us our calculation of the partial of s with respect to b.
然后，这就是给我们计算相对于b的s的部分。
And so we can see that the- the identity matrix sort of goes
所以我们可以看到 - 身份矩阵的类型
away so we end up with this composition of ht times f prime of z.
因此我们最终得到了这个组成的ht次f的z。
Okay, suppose we then want to go on and compute now the partial of s with respect to w?
好吧，假设我们现在想继续计算关于w的部分s？
Well, as starting off point is
那么，起点就是
exactly the same chain rule that we work out each of the stages.
我们计算出每个阶段完全相同的链规则。
So, that first of all you're working
所以，首先你要工作
out the z from the wx part then putting it through the non linearity,
从wx部分输出z，然后通过非线性，
then doing the dot product of the vectors.
然后做矢量的点积。
So that part is the same.
那部分是一样的。
And what you should notice is that if you
而你应该注意的是，如果你
compare the partial of s with respect to w versus s with respect to b,
比较s的部分关于w与s的关系，
most of them are the same and it's only the part at the end that's different.
他们中的大多数是相同的，只有最后的部分是不同的。
And that sort of makes sense in terms of our neural net right?
从神经网络的角度来看，那种有意义吗？
That when we had our neural net that the w and the b were coming in here.
当我们拥有神经网络时，w和b进入这里。
And once you've sort of done some stuff with them you're putting things through
一旦你用它们做了一些事情，你就会把事情做好
the same activation function and doing the same dot product to create a score.
相同的激活功能和做同样的点积来创建得分。
So, you're sort of doing the same calculations that you're then composing with.
所以，你有点做你正在编写的计算。
So it sort of makes sense that you should be getting
所以你应该得到它是有道理的
the same derivatives that are
相同的衍生物
occur- same partial derivatives that occurring at that point.
发生 - 在该点发生的相同偏导数。
Oops. And so effectively you know
哎呀。你知道的有效
these partial dev- derivatives correspond to
这些部分dev-衍生物对应于
the computations in the neural network that are above where w and b are.
神经网络中高于w和b的计算。
And so those are commonly referred to as delta,
所以这些通常被称为delta，
note delta which is different from partial derivative d. And so
注意delta与偏导数d不同。所以
delta is referred to as the error signal and neural network talk.
delta被称为误差信号和神经网络对话。
So, it's the what you're calculating as
所以，这就是你在计算的东西
the partial derivatives above
上面的偏导数
the parameters that you are working out the partial derivatives with respect to.
你正在计算的偏导数的参数。
So, a lot of the secret as we'll see next time,
所以，我们下次会看到很多秘密，
a lot of the secret of what happens with backpropagation is
反向传播发生的很多秘密就是
just we want to do efficient computation in
只是我们想要进行有效的计算
the sort of way that's computer science people like to do efficient computation.
那种计算机科学人喜欢进行高效计算的方式。
And so precisely what we want to notice is that there is
所以我们要注意的是，确实存在
one error signal that comes from above and we want to compute it once.
一个错误信号来自上面，我们想要计算一次。
And then reuse that when calculating
然后在计算时重用它
both partial derivatives with respect to w and with b.
关于w和b的偏导数。
Okay. So there's sort of two things to still do.
好的。所以还有两件事要做。
So one is well,
一个人很好，
it'd be kind of useful to know what the partial derivative
知道偏导数是什么有用
of s with respect to w actually looks like.
关于w的s实际上看起来像。
I mean, is that a number, a vector,
我的意思是，这是一个数字，一个矢量，
a matrix, a three-dimensional tensor?
矩阵，三维张量？
And then we actually want to work out its values
然后我们实际上想要弄清楚它的价值观
and to work out its values we're going to still have to work
为了弄清楚它的价值，我们仍然需要努力
out the partial derivative of z with respect to
出z的偏导数
w. But if first of all we just try and work out its shape,
W上。但是，如果我们首先尝试找出它的形状，
what kind of shape does it have?
它有什么样的形状？
And this is actually sort of a bit tricky and is
这实际上有点棘手
sort of a dirty underbelly of doing this kind of matrix calculus.
做这种矩阵演算的一种肮脏的下腹部。
So, since our weight vector is an n by m matrix,
所以，因为我们的权重向量是一个n乘m矩阵，
the end result of the partial of s with respect to w is we have a function with
关于w的部分s的最终结果是我们有一个函数
n times m inputs all of the elements of w and simply one output which is our score.
n次m输入w的所有元素，只输出一个输出，这是我们的分数。
So, that makes it sound like according to what I said before we
所以，这听起来像我之前所说的那样
should have a one by n times m Jacobian.
应该有一个n倍m雅可比。
But it turns out that's not really what we want, right?
但事实证明，这不是我们想要的，对吗？
Because what we wanted to do is use what we calculate
因为我们想要做的是使用我们计算的东西
inside this stochastic gradient descent update algorithm.
在这个随机梯度下降更新算法中。
And if we're doing this with sort of like to have
如果我们这样做有点喜欢
the old weight matrix and we'd like to subtract a bit format to get a new weight matrix.
旧的权重矩阵，我们想减去一点格式来获得一个新的权重矩阵。
So, be kind of nice if the shape of our Jacobian was the same shape as w. And so we-
所以，如果雅各布的形状和w的形状相同，那就太好了。所以我们 -
we and in general what you always want to do with
我们以及一般您想要做的事情
neural nets is follow what we call the shape convention which
神经网络遵循我们称之为形状约定的方式
is we're going to sort of represent the Jacobian so it's in the same shape as the inputs.
我们是否会代表Jacobian，所以它与输入的形状相同。
And this whole thing is kind of the- the bad part of
而这一切都是 - 不好的一部分
the bad part of doing matrix calculus.
做矩阵演算的不好的部分。
Like there's a lot of inconsistency as to how people represent matrix calculus.
就像人们如何表示矩阵演算一样，存在很多不一致之处。
That in general if you just go to different fields like
一般来说，如果你只是去不同的领域，如
economics and physics some people use a numerator convention.
经济学和物理学有些人使用分子约定。
Some people use a denominator convention.
有些人使用分母惯例。
We're using neither of those.
我们都没有使用这些。
We're going to use this shape convention so we match the shape of
我们将使用这种形状约定，因此我们匹配的形状
the input so it makes it easy to do our weight updates.
输入因此可以轻松进行重量更新。
Okay. So. Right. So that's what we want the answer to look like.
好的。所以。对。这就是我们想要的答案。
So, then the final thing we need to do to work out on the
那么，最后我们需要做的就是解决这个问题
partial of s with respect to w is we have the error signal delta
相对于w的部分s是我们有误差信号delta
that's gonna be part of the answer and then we want to work out the partial
这将是答案的一部分，然后我们想要解决部分问题
of z with respect to w. Well,
关于w的z。好，
um what's that going to be.
那将是什么样的。
Well, it turns out and I'm about to be
好吧，事实证明，我即将成为
saved by the bell here since I'm down to two minutes left.
因为我还剩下两分钟就被钟声保存了。
Um, it turns out that what we end up with for that is we take
嗯，事实证明我们最终得到的就是我们
the product of the partial- the product of delta times x.
部分的乘积 -  delta乘以x的乘积。
So effectively we've got the local error signal above w. And then we
因此，我们有效地获得了高于w的本地错误信号。然后我们
have the inputs x and we are working out an outer product of them.
有输入x，我们正在研究它们的外部产品。
And the sort of way to think about this is sort of for the w's.
而考虑这种情况的方式就像w一样。
You know, we've got the elements of the w matrix,
你知道，我们已经得到了w矩阵的元素，
these different connections between our neurons.
这些不同神经元之间的联系。
And so each one of these is connecting one output to one input.
因此，每个都将一个输出连接到一个输入。
And so we're going to be sort of making this n by
所以我们将会有点像这样做
m matrix of our partial derivatives that are going to be the product of
我们的偏导数的矩阵将成为
the error signal for the appropriate output
适当输出的错误信号
multiplied by input and those goes give us the partial derivatives.
乘以输入，那些给我们的偏导数。
I'm skipping ahead quickly in my last one minute.
我在最后一分钟快速跳过了。
Okay. So uh, right.
好的。嗯，对。
So this is sort of what I said have used
所以这就是我所说过的
the shape con- convention. I'm going to skip that.
形状公约。我要跳过那个。
Okay. So, um, I- I ran out of time a teeny bit at the end but I mean,
好的。所以，嗯，我 - 最后我的时间不多了，但我的意思是，
I think hopefully that's conveyed most of
我希望大部分都能传达出来
the idea of how you can sort of use the chain rule and
关于如何使用链规则的想法
work out the derivatives and work them out in
找出衍生品并将其解决
terms of these vector and matrix derivatives.
这些向量和矩阵导数的术语。
[NOISE] And essentially what we wanna do for backpropagation is to say how can we
[NOISE]基本上我们想做的反向传播就是说我们怎么做
do ah get a computer to do this automatically for us and to do it efficiently.
做啊让计算机自动为我们这样做，并有效地做到这一点。
And that's what's sort of the deep learning frameworks like
这就是深度学习框架之类的东西
TensorFlow and PyTorch do and how you can do that.
TensorFlow和PyTorch以及如何做到这一点。
We'll look at more next time.
我们下次会看更多。